

Adelaide South Australia

0434 235 289 hello@mariahlattas.com

www.mariahlattas.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mariahlattas

12 February 1998

Objective

A 22-year-old journalist, podcaster, and graduate from Adelaide, South Australia. Currently a content writer, podcast host and producer and Ryderwear and the PUSHH app. Co-host and journalist on *The Milkbar* by postup and *Pink Rabbit* on Radio Adelaide and JOY 94.9. I am passionate about telling important stories and giving a voice to those who do not have the ability and to hold those who do have a voice accountable.

Experience

Content Writer and Executive Producer & Host, What The Flex? at Ryderwear and PUSHH — 2020-Present

Ryderwear is an Adelaide based activewear company. My role includes writing content for the Ryderwear blog, website, emails, and any other content required. For Ryderwear, I am the Executive Producer and Host of the *What The Flex?* YouTube and audio podcast. Furthermore, I take care of the News Feed for the PUSHH Fitness app, keeping users up to date in the latest health and fitness news.

Co-host, The Milkbar at postup — 2019-Present

postup is an independent, youth-centric media company based in Adelaide focusing on culture and sport. The Milkbar is a podcast about culture co-hosted with Benito Carbone. Covering culture and current affairs, produced weekly.

Journalist and Host, Pink Rabbit at Radio Adelaide — 2018-Present

A 21st century feminist podcast broadcast weekly on Radio Adelaide 101.5FM and Joy 94.9 FM in Melbourne. Serving as both journalist and host with Milly Shultz-Boylen, Soph Landau and Phoebe Montgomery. Through Pink Rabbit, I have extensive skills researching and producing original stories for live and pre-recorded broadcast including live panel discussions both in studio and to live audiences.

Journalist, The Wire at Radio Adelaide - 2018

Covered news and current affairs, writing, interviewing, producing and voicing multiple packages that were syndicated to five radio stations nationally: 2SER in Sydney; 4EB in Brisbane; CAAMA RADIO Alice Springs; RTR-FM in Perth; and JOY 94.9 in Melbourne.

Operations Specialist at Apple — 2017-2019

In more recent role from October 2018. Previous role: Product Specialist. Oversees the daily operations and inventory management of South Australia's only Apple Retail Store.

Placement at Channel 7 Adelaide - 2018

University placement working mainly with political journalist, Mike Smithson, working on stories primarily related to politics.

Placement at Channel 10 Adelaide - 2018

University placement shadowing multiple journalists and working with the newsroom.

Media and Communications Manager at Adelaide Cobras Football Club – 2016-2017 Covering all communications for the club including social media accounts and writing stories and articles for the club's website and communications as well as communicating with the rest of the board to ensure the digital presence of the club was reflecting the direction of the club.

Education

University of Adelaide; Bachelor of Media and Bachelor of Arts, Major in Politics and International Relations - 2016-2019

In 2017, studied at the University of Adelaide's Singapore campus under a New Colombo Plan Scholarship. Also, completed a short course at Seisen University, Japan in 2019 and in 2020 completing a politics 2-week study tour to Illinois and Iowa Caucus in the United States to cover and observe the 2020 Presidential Election Primary campaigns.

University Senior College; Stage 1 and 2 SACE — 2014-2015

Immanuel College — 2007-2013

Key Skills

Writing, researching, producing and editing pre-recorded packages for radio broadcast.

Strong interviewing skills with the ability to distil and summarise the interviewees words to form a concise story.

Experience with live radio broadcasting and written workflows and tools.

Built and developed a new podcast from scratch with in a start-up organisation environment.

Expansive world political and cultural awareness and experience, well travelled and highly educated on political frameworks and theories as they apply to the current landscape.

Placements and experience in traditional news media — Channel 7 and Channel 10. With experience in new and online media — postup. And community media — Radio Adelaide.

References

Benito Carbone Co-founder, postup. and Co-host, The Milkbar 0450 001 705 benito@postup.com.au

Nikki Marcel
People and Programs Manager, Radio Adelaide
08 7132 5000
nikki.marcel@radioadelaide.org.au

Georgia Roberts

Presenter, ABC Broken Hill
0410 711 030

roberts.georgia@abc.net.au